SURAJ VERMA

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

DETAILS

PHONE

+91 7016185829

EMAIL

surajj.verma7@gmail.com

LANGUAGES

English

Hindi

LINKS

Email

Linkedin

<u>Github</u>

Portfolio Website

<u>Telegram</u>

SKILLS

React.js

Next.js

Node.js

Express.js

Mongodb

Apache Cassandra

Dart

Flutter

Netlify

Heroku

GitHub

Gitlab

Solidity

PROFILE

Experienced and self-motivated Student. Bringing forth a motivated attitude and a variety of powerful skills. Adept in various social media platforms and office technology programs. Committed to utilizing my skills to further the mission of a company.

WORK HISTORY

Full Stack Engineer, Grroom

Oct 2020 — Mar 2022

Technology Used: React.js, Node.js, Heroku, AWS, SES, Sendgrid, Twilio SMS, Firebase, Digital Ocean, MongoDB, Mongoose, Webhooks, Queue Manager, Socket.io, GitHub, Ubuntu.

What I Built:

- · Build Backed for Full Fleage AI stylist & Sale Tracker.
- · Intregrate ML Apis in Backend.
- · Built a better Design System from start to end (Scalability).

Responsibility:

- · Worked with different Cloud Platform for hosting API and websites
- Followed the best practices while developing the app and also kept everything structured and well documented.
- Managed code and projects on GitHub to keep in sync with other team members and managers.
- Communicated with the Product Manager regarding the status of projects and suggested appropriate deadlines for new functionalities.

Flutter & Node.js Developer, Furballs Veterinary App

Aug 2021 — Feb 2022

Technology Used: Flutter, Node.js, Heroku, Firebase, Digital Ocean, MongoDB, Mongoose, GitHub, Ubuntu.

Responsibility:

- I built Admin & Client App using Flutter with dynamic data tables & Admin
 Create multiple articles in multiple sections & Dynamic Firebase notification.
- · Worked with different Hosting Sites and Email Providers.
- · Handle Different types of data in different sections based on roles.
- · Take decisions about application flows & structure.
- · Managed Push notifications and Email Queues.

Flutter Developer, Pixel Apps

May 2021 — Sep 2021

Technology Used: Dart, Flutter (2.0), Firebase, FCM, Figma, In-vision, Provider, Getx, Riverpod.

Responsibilities:

- Designing, developing, testing, deploying, supporting, and evolving hybrid applications.
- · Proposing and reviewing system designs and evaluating alternatives.
- Participating in software architectural, designing, and code review discussions for new applications.
- Debugging existing software components, fixing issues, and avoiding regressions.
- Focusing on component reusability, data sharing, and security while complying with Enterprise standards and processes.

Backend & NFT Developer, Frshr Technologies

Apr 2021 — Jul 2021

Technology Used: Node.js, Express.js, MongoDB, GIT, Ubuntu, Hedera Hashgraph, Google API.

What I Built: Here I worked on two software. 1. ATS (Applicant Tracking System), 2. Social Media with NFT marketplace.

Responsibilities:

- Resolved any problems existing in the system; suggested and added new features in the complete system.
- Ensured that security best practices and guidelines are followed while developing the application.
- Maintained software through product lifecycle including design, development, verification, and bug fixes.

Full Stack Developer, OETD Labs

Jan 2021 — Apr 2021

Technology Used: Send Grid, Twillio, Razor Pay, Node.js, Express.js, HTML, CSS, MongoDB, Firebase Cloud Messages (FCM), AWS EC2, GIT, Ubuntu.

What I Built: The back-end for Drop shipping application using which users can transfer documents or parcels things through local peoples and Done Server-side rendering for some pages.

Responsibilities:

- Develop Server Side logic (API) with Server-side rendering. Compile and analyze data, processes, and codes to troubleshoot problems and identify areas for improvement.
- Collaborating with the front-end developers and other team members to establish objectives and design more functional, cohesive codes to enhance the user experience.

Full Stack Developer, Simply Turn

Aug 2020 — Dec 2020

Technology Used: Node.js, Heroku, Corn Job, MongoDB, Mongoose, GitHub, Git-lab, FCM, Mail Trap, Socket.io, React.js, Netlify, CSS, Ubuntu.

What I built: Back-end for full-fledged HRMS software with multiple cutting edge features, Fronted for Sign-up Page.

Responsibility:

- Collaborate with **Front-end** developers to integrate user-facing elements with server-side logic.
- Compile and analyze data, processes, and codes to troubleshoot problems and identify areas for improvement.
- Develop Over 250+ REST full APIs.
- · Fulfill the requirement of fronted Develop.

Backend & Blockchain Developer, OETD Labs

Aug 2020 — Oct 2020

Technology Used: Node.js, AWS, Corn Job, MongoDB, Mongoose, GitHub, Ubuntu.

What I built: Back-end for full-fledged blockchain-based application, where users can store, trade, and send different cryptocurrencies.

Responsibility:

- Collaborate with Front-end developers to integrate user-facing elements with server-side logic.
- Compile and analyze data, processes, and codes to troubleshoot problems and identify areas for improvement.
- · Develop logic to store and manage **transactions** & wallets.
- · Develop efficient API for Blockchain-based Call.

Backend Developer, Code Variac

Jul 2020 — Sep 2020

Technology Used: Node.js, Heroku, MongoDB, Mongoose, GitHub, Ubuntu.

What I built: Back-end for multiple E commerce application.

Responsibility:

- · Troubleshoot and **debug** applications.
- · Gather and address technical requirements.
- · Write **clean code** to develop functional web applications.
- · Liaise with designers, and the client to identify new features.
- · Manage cutting-edge technologies to improve legacy applications.
- Participate in the entire application life cycle, focusing on coding and debugging.

Full Stack Team Lead, Naaniz

Jun 2020 — Aug 2020

Technology Used: React.js, Node.js, Heroku, Firebase, Firebase Hosting, MongoDB, Mongoose, Netfliy, GitHub, Ubuntu.

Responsibility:

- My responsibilities were decision-making, coaching, mentoring, developing the team's skills, and managing conflict, overall oversee the functionality of a workgroup by providing guidance and instruction.
- · Successfully handle a Team of 13 people.
- · Take decisions about application flows & structure.
- · Developed Node.js and React.js Application.

EDUCATION

B-Tech, Parul University

Vadodara

Jul 2018 — Jul 2022

Current Score: 8.09 CGPA